- 慢点！ - 你快点儿，杰克！
Come on, Jake, slow down. Hurry up.
- 梅兰妮！ - 带我回家！
Melanie!
-片名：情归阿拉巴马
我妈妈会杀了我的！
We gotta get home or Mom's gonna kill me.
- 哇，你看到了吗？ - 一千零一
Wow, did you see that?
一千零二，一千零三…
1,001 , 1,002. . .
- 回答我的问题！ - 不！
- Answer the question! - No!
不，你是不想回答 还是不想嫁给我？
No, you won't answer, or you won't marry me?
杰克佩里，我才10岁 我的生活有太多的将来
Jake Perry, I'm ten years old. I got too much to live for.
你不能去那边，过来！
Not that way, you don't. Come on!
- 哇！真酷 - 很烫，别碰它
Wow! Cool. It's hot. Don't touch it.
- 我们在这里是安全的 - 谁说的？
We'll be safe here. Says who?
大家都这么说
Everybody.
闪电不会两次 击中同一个地方
Lightning never strikes the same place twice.
你到底为什么要娶我呢？
Why would you want to marry me, anyhow?
那样我就可以 想亲你就亲你了
So I can kiss you any time I want.
Oh, my God.
Hi.
你说梦话的时候 口音更重了
That accent of yours is a lot thicker when you're dreaming.
- 你怎么能让我睡着呢？ - 放松，才五分钟
How come y'all let me sleep?
我说什么了？
- Calm down. It was five minutes. - What did I say?
说等你成了大人物时 我们就能加薪了
We're all getting big raises when you become somebody.
他们弄死了 巴杰利密斯奇卡了吗？
Did they kill Badgley Mischka.
尽管笑吧 明天就该轮到我们了
Laugh now, tomorrow it could be us.
不是我们，是你 我只是个冲咖啡的
Not us, you. I just make the coffee.
谢谢
Thank you.
感谢你们工作了整整一夜 发布会时见
Thanks for the long night. I'll see you at the show. See you later. Get some rest.
安德鲁！
Andrew.
你好，亲爱的，早上好
Honey, there's a rose for every moment I thought of you last night.
昨晚我想到你时 每分每秒都有玫瑰的味道
你一定累坏了 发布会时见
You must be exhausted. Knock 'em dead.
一定会很成功的，我爱你 我等不及想见你了
I'll see you at the show. It's gonna be great. I love you. I can't wait to see you. Goodbye.
好了，各位 我们真的晚了
OK, people we are officially late!
- 梅兰妮 - 在
- Melanie! - Yes?
这件上衣应该是电光紫色
This top is supposed to be neon aubergine
可这根本不是！
but it's all wrong!
别慌，这是我的工作 艾纽克上场后再穿它
OK, don't panic. That's my job. Put her on after Anouk.
第三个提示灯是黄色的 衣服就会显得是茄子紫了
The light cue is yellow. She'll look eggplant.
颜色不对的原因是 你们穿反了
Pan, it's wrong because it's on backwards.
戴西小姐，我真怕了你了
Miss Dixie, I'm scared of you!
弗雷德里克，你在这里干什么？ 你可是竞争对手
Frederick, why are you here? You're the competition.
拜托，我和我的女学生之间 可不会有什么竞争
Competition? Please! Our designs are pearls. Nothing comes between me and my protegee.
而这个，完全就是属于我的
This is, after all, all about me.
我喜欢这个 斯特拉麦卡特尼要不行了
I love this. Stella McCartney's gonna kill herself.
我感觉就像裸身站在 泰晤士广场上
Why do I feel like I'm in Times Square, naked?
你很棒，七年前 你才从农庄里出来
You'll be fine. Seven years ago, you were a debutante off the plantation.
现在你已经是我的铿锵玫瑰 要开自己的发布会了
Now you're my steel magnolia, with her very own show.
在你把我弄哭之前 赶快离开这里
Get out before you make me cry.
Bonne chance.
Secretary Hennings, do you have a moment?
拜托，告诉我他真的那么完美吗
Please tell me he has a flaw somewhere.
他请我去爱尔兰过圣诞节
He asked me to go to Ireland for Christmas.
他要请你做的事情 比这个多多了
He's going to ask you a lot more than that.
你这样想？
You think so?
好了，我们得走了
- It's time, let's do this. - Alright, we got to go.
大家请就位 开始，排好队
Places, everyone.
好，不要微笑 保持傻笑
Let's go. Line up. OK, don't smile. No smiles, just smirks.
Wait.
OK, go.
亲爱的！
Honey!
- 恭喜 - 你太棒了
- Congratulations. - You're amazing.
- 那些花儿令人发疯 - 我希望这是完美的一天
- The flowers were insane. - I want this day to be perfect.
他们讨厌我怎么办？
- God, what if they hate me?
他们是批评家，连自己都讨厌
- Critics hate themselves.Easy for you to say.
我可不是生来就有 亨宁斯家的厚脸皮
I don't have thick Hennings skin.
当然不是 我就是喜欢你这一点
No, you don't. And that is what I love about you.
抱歉，我要去见个人 你好好享受现在
I'm sorry. I have a meeting. You enjoy it and I'll see you later.
喂，我们今晚在林肯中心 还要谈那件事
We've got that thing tonight at Lincoln Center.
- 谈什么？ - 融资的事
- What thing? - Fundraiser thing.
很好，就谈这个，和你妈妈 今晚
Right. The thing. With your mother. That's tonight.
- 恐怕是 - 好啊
- I'm afraid so. - OK.
我真为你骄傲
I am so proud of you.
谢谢
- Thank you. - OK.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你，恭喜你
- I love you. - I love you, too. Congratulations.
他的会面要耽搁了 你想进去等吗？
His meeting's running late. He told me to take you inside.
我们现在在哪里？
Where are we?
我太累了，吉米 我已经够了
- I'm so tired, Jimmy. - Yeah.
他不会太久了
- I've just had it. - He shouldn't be too long.
卡迈克尔小姐 请进来好吗？
Miss Carmichael, won't you come in?
你做出决定了吗？
So, have you made a decision?
- 什么决定？ - 爱尔兰
- About what? - Ireland.
爱尔兰，亲爱的？ 那还有4个月呢
Ireland, honey? That's four months from now.
我想可能有
I was thinking maybe. . .
200位客人，最多300位
. ..2-300 guests, tops.
圣诞节？安德鲁 你吃错药了吗？
For Christmas? Are you on some sort of medication?
怎么回事？ 我们这是在哪里？
What's going on? Where are we?
蒂芙尼公司
噢，天啊
Oh, my God!
梅兰妮卡迈克尔
Melanie Carmichael,
你愿意嫁给我吗？
will you marry me?
你是说真的吗？
Are you sure? I mean, are you really sure?
如果你不确定 我们可以回到车上去
If you're not, we can just go back to the car.
- 才8个月… - 你知道我从来不鲁莽行事
- It's only been eight months. - I never do anything rash.
我也不会提出一个 我不知道答案的问题
I never ask a question I don't know the answer to.
冒着被拒绝两次的危险
So at the risk of being rejected twice,
我再问你一次
I'm gonna ask you again.
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
愿意
Yes.
挑一个吧
Pick one.
市长夫人！
- Mayor, just one shot. - Over here, Mayor.
- 他在哪儿？ - 他迟到了
- Where is he? - Running late.
肯定又是去找 那个姓卡班克尔的女孩了
Thanks to that Carbuncle girl.
是卡迈克尔 南部的设计师
- Carmichael, designer, Southern.
对，管她姓什么
- Whatever.
您如何答复那些反对您的
Your Honour, how do you answer
道路改善项目的人？
those who oppose your street-improvement project?
我建议他们开车穿过 布鲁克林大街试试
I suggest they drive through Brooklyn.
说不定就会掉进地洞里
Maybe they'll disappear in a pothole.
有消息说您儿子和梅兰妮卡迈克尔 订婚了，您对此有什么看法？
Sources say your son's engaged to Melanie Carmichael. Do you have a comment?
相信我，如果我儿子真订婚了 我早就发表看法了
Trust me if my son were engaged, I'd have a comment.
- 我想你累了 - 吉米，给我们点儿隐私
- I thought you were tired. - Jimmy, excuse us.
我为此已经计划好几个星期了 一切都很完美
I planned this for weeks. This thing tonight is perfect.
我等不及地想看 我妈妈脸上的表情
I can't wait to see my mother's face.
- 给你父母打个电话 - 不要！
- Come on, let's call your parents. - No!
我是说…不要现在打
I mean, not right this second.
我们自己享受 几天这个秘密怎么样？
What I mean is, would you mind if we kept this to ourselves for a few days?
公开是早晚的事
Mel, it'll come out sooner or later.
我知道，但是我已经 有七年没见过我父母了
I know but I haven't seen my folks in about seven years.
我觉得我应该当面告诉他们
I just feel like I should probably tell them in person.
当然了
Of course.
我想自己去说
And I think I should do it alone.
梅兰妮，我早晚都要见他们的
Mel, I'll have to meet them eventually.
我知道，他们会喜欢你的 慢慢会的
I know. And they will love you. Eventually.
因为我是北方人？
- Is it because I'm a Yankee?
哦，是，还是民主党人
- Well, that, and a Democrat.
好吧，我们保守秘密
OK. Mum's the word.
- 没人会知道 - 谢谢你
- No one will know. - Thank you.
Secretary Hennings.
Hello.
Have you told your mother you're engaged?
抱歉我们来晚了
Sorry we're late.
- 你怎么耽搁了？ - 不关你事
That lipstick doesn't suit you. What kept you? - None of your business.
我不喜欢惊喜 告诉我怎么回事？
- What's going on?
我是汤姆，非常荣幸
Tom, always a pleasure. Good to see you.
我是梅兰妮，幸会
Melanie, darling. So good to see you.
永远的舞会皇后
Look at you, the belle of the ball.
关于你的新设计 我听到很多赞美
I hear your new line is good.
哦，多谢
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
安德鲁，梅兰妮的重要手指上 戴着一个大钻戒
- Andrew. - Yes? Melanie is wearing a skating rink on an important finger.
其实这没什么…
- I'd like to keep this. . . - Oh, my God!
天啊，你们订婚了？
You're engaged?
小点声
. .quiet.
他们订婚了！ 纽约城爱情洋溢
他名草有主！
姑娘们，死了心吧！
市长的儿子及 婚纱设计界的公主
我们是朋友 我却和其他一千两百万人一起知道
I'm your first New York friend and I read about it with 1 2 million other people.
她突然抓住我的手 我还能怎么办？
Sorry. She grabbed my hand. What could I do?
- 我知道，你哭了吗？ - 换作是你会吗？
I know. We read about it. Did you cry? Wouldn't you?
我会哭到眼睛流血的 你怎么不来和我们一起？
One man for the rest of my life? I'd bawl. Come and meet us.
不行啊，我在阿拉巴马
I can't. I'm in Alabama.
噢，天啊
Oh, my God.
是啊
Yeah.
欢迎来到格林维尔
欢迎来到鸽子湾
莫家渔业
它叫的声音大，但不咬人 过来！别叫了，狗狗
He's loud, but he don't bite. Shut up, hound
趴下
Lie down.
别动！
Come on, stay.
需要我帮什么忙吗？
How can I help you?
你可以过来跟我离婚
Well, you can get your stubborn ass down here and give me a divorce.
杰克，我是认真的 胡闹该结束了，我还要去赶飞机
Jake, I mean it. The joke's over. Let's finish this. I've got a plane to catch.
你和我开玩笑吧？
You're shitting me, right?
我从来不理解这种粗话 但是，对，不是开玩笑
I never understood that expression, but no, I'm not shitting you.
我还有些愚蠢的标签 可以让事情简化一点儿
Look, it's even got these idiot-proof tabs to make it easy.
有我的一份，你的一份 还有律师的一份
One copy for me, one for you, one for the lawyers.
什么？说吧
What? Speak.
你离开了七年 现在又突然出现，却不肯说一句
You show up here after seven years
“嗨，杰克，还记得我吗？ 我是你老婆？”或者
without so much as a, "Hey, there, Jake. Remember me, your wife?"
“嗨，亲爱的，看起来不错啊 家里人怎么样？”
Or, "Hi, honey. Looking good. How's the family?"
你希望我说你看起来不错？ 你没香皂用了吧？
You expect me to say you look good? Did the Piggly Wiggly run out of soap?
你在的地方 这样会被嘲笑吗？
They laugh at that up north, or wherever you've been?
你知道我在哪儿 却从来不假装一下你想我
You knew where I was. And don't pretend you missed me.
我曾经想过你，好吧 但在这一阶段，我的目标提高了
I missed you. But at this range, my aim is bound to improve.
这是威胁吗？
Is that a threat?
每次你把这些文件退回去
I've got a lawyer charges $350 an hour.
我的律师每小时要收费350块
He billed me every time you sent these back.
我很高兴你得到了消息
I'm glad you got the message.
- 别叫了，熊熊！ - 别叫了，布赖恩特！
- Shut up, Bear! - Shut up, Bryant!
熊熊哪儿去了？
What happened to Bear?
它死了，你却不在
He died. You weren't here.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
我要离开，这还看不明白
Leaving. You should recognise the gesture.
我们就不能 理智点儿解决问题吗？
Could we try to keep this as civilised as possible?
请你在这些文件上签字 我就能回家了
Please sign these so I can go home.
“家？”我打赌你父母 还不知道你回来了
What do you know from home? I bet your folks don't know you're here.
那是我的事
That's my business.
亲爱的，他们才是你唯一的家人
Honey, those people are the only family you got.
别叫我“亲爱的”
Don't "honey" me, honey!
开车去见见你的父母
Get your butt back in that car,
然后我们或许可以谈谈
drive over and see 'em, then maybe we'll talk.
杰克！你这个 愚蠢顽固的乡下人！
Jake! You dumb, stubborn, redneck hick!
你不想签字的唯一原因就是 我想让你签
You won't sign these cos I want you to!
我不签字的唯一理由是
Wrong! I ain't signing
你已经变成了 一个虚伪傲慢的北方娘们
cos you've turned into some hoity-toity Yankee bitch
我就是要让你不痛快
and I'd like nothing better than to piss you off!
莫斯莱德尔的飞机 被你搞成什么了？
What are you doing with Mo SlideI's plane?
那是我的事
- That's my business! - Fine!
- 很好 - 很好
Fine!
离婚，离个鬼啊
Divorce, my ass.
嘿，天才
Hey, genius.
下次你想把某人锁在门外时 记得把备用钥匙藏起来
When you lock somebody out, make sure they don't know where the spare key is.
我就要这样藏钥匙
Well, see, that's the thing about hide-a-keys.
如果有老婆可以告诉自己 钥匙在哪里多好
It'd be nice if your wife told you where it was.
我不是你老婆，杰克
I'm not your wife, Jake.
我只是第一个上了你卡车 车斗的女孩
I'm just the first girl that climbed in the back of your truck.
但是你说得对 我是变了
But you're right.
我已经不记得以前的自己了
I have changed. I don't even know that girl any more.
哦，那允许我提示你一下吧
Well, then, allow me to remind you.
出生于阿拉巴马格林维尔 一个富有之家
"Born into one of the wealthiest families of Greenville, Alabama,
“她父亲做棉花及所有相关生意”
her daddy's in cotton and all that that implies."
格林维尔没有厄尔卡迈克尔的 家族表
There is no listing for an Earl Carmichael in Greenville.
她读的当地高中呢？
Her high school?
没有梅兰妮卡迈克尔的记录
No record of Melanie Carmichael attending, ever.
天啊，向来可靠的新闻业 是怎么了？
Jesus! Whatever happened to responsible journalism?
一定有哪里不对劲儿
Something's wrong here.
我儿子为什么要这样对我呢？
Why would my son do this to me?
也许他爱她
Maybe he loves her?
噢，拜托 这是典型的伤心后遗症
Please! This is classic rebound.
他上次分手的伤还没好呢 那是和…
He's hurt from breaking up with. . . Who was it?
惠特尼楚斯戴尔 旧金山的律师
Whitney Trusdale, lawyer, San Francisco.
他们才是天作之合
Yeah. There was a match made in heaven.
加利福尼亚的上流社会 有政治背景的家庭
Society, political family, California.
所有的选举人都会投票的
All those electoral votes.
给安德鲁打电话
Get Andrew on the phone.
住房部长能给我们的时间不多
We only have a small window for the Secretary of Housing.
Hold your questions until after the presentation.
你看到我妈妈的表情了吗？
See the look on my Mom's face?
- 我觉得她的头都会爆炸 - 她说什么了？
I thought her head would explode.What'd she say?
和梅兰妮那样的女孩约会 但不能娶她们
I should date women like Mel, not marry them.
- 真苛刻 - 这就是妈妈
- That's harsh. - That's Mom.
- Thank you. - Thanks a lot.
说来就来了
We hope to have the Bronx Children's Hospital open. . . Speak of the devil. Hello.
你们这对新人定了日子没有？
So, have you lovebirds set a date?
我请求第五次修订案
I plead the Fifth.
尽量保守你的秘密
Try to keep your secrets, I dare you.
你的语气听起来好多了
You're in a better mood.
我的支持率增加了 公众喜欢我做好母亲的角色
My approval rating went up two points. The public likes to know I'm a mother.
- 又是为了你的竞选 - 我只是为你考虑
- Always running for office. - I'm only thinking of you. Say...
你有卡迈克尔 在格林维尔的号码吗？
Do you have the Carmichaels' number down there in Greenville?
- 我想打个问候电话 - 我都没见过他们呢
I thought I should introduce myself. I'd like to meet them first.
媒体会大肆渲染 相信我的话没错
The press will be all over this. Take it from me.
幸福的一对儿不会有看点
Happy couples don't sell.
要是她家里有什么秘密的话 我们得知道才行
If there are any skeletons in her closet, we need to know about them.
你做衣服，对不对？
You make clothes, right?
我设计衣服，这有很大区别
I design them. There's a big difference.
设计有条纹的衣服？
You design anything with stripes?
你给警长打电话了？ 你知道那个老家伙讨厌我
You called the sheriff? You know that old bastard hates me.
讨厌得有道理
For good reason.
这不是罪犯梅兰妮吗？
Well, hell's bells! If it ain't Felony Melanie.
- 韦德？ - 真是你啊，姑娘！
Wade?
我们都想死你了！
Hot damn, girl, do we miss you around here.
我想我有天见到了 可怜的老福兹
I saw poor Fuzz the other day.
你最好别说 我不敢相信你是警长了！
You had to bring that up. So, you're the Sheriff?
我每天搜搜你这样的小美女的身 就可以领到工资
I get to frisk pretty things like you and get paid for it.
你得专业点儿 我们这儿可有个嫌疑犯
Try and be more professional. We got a crime suspect here.
你不能随便闯进别人的家里
You can't break into people's houses.
我不是闯进来的 我是用钥匙开的
I didn't break in. I used a key.
我的钥匙
My key.
这也不是你的家 我得把你驱逐出去
It still ain't your house. I'll have to escort you out.
用拳头啊
Use the cuffs.
你要是能让他在这些文件上签字 就可以把我驱逐出镇子
If you get him to sign these, you can run me out of town.
- 这不是你的事 - 这是什么文件？
- That's not your concern. - What do we got here?
离婚协议，女士？
A bill of divorcement?
- 我以为你签过了呢 - 我也以为呢
- You said you took care of this. - I thought I had.
很明显，没有
Obviously not.
如果你们还有婚姻关系 这就是她的房子
If you are still married, it's her house too.
这只是家庭内部矛盾
This ain't nothing but a domestic dispute.
他打你了吗？ 我可以立刻把他带走
He didn't hit you, did he? If he did, I'll take him in.
这种问题我们很重视
We take that stuff pretty serious nowadays.
没有，韦德 杰克从没打过我
No, Wade. Jake's never hit me.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我每段童年的记忆 里面都有你们
Every childhood memory I have has you two in it.
有个晚上我把自己的屁股点着了 你记得吗？
Including the night I lit my ass on fire.
记忆之门关闭了
Wade, Memory Lane is closed.
你们两个当时多缠绵啊
You two got a whole lot of catching up to do. I'll leave you to it.
你为什么就不签字呢？
- I set you up with your wife. - Sign the papers!
我无能为力 法律就是法律
I can't do anything. The law is the law.
她没有任何过失
She has done nothing wrong.
那在戴西店里偷拿牛排 不算犯罪了？
So shoplifting steaks at Winn-Dixie is OK?
我送回去了，你知道的！
You know I took them back!
那在牲畜栏里破坏公物呢？ 都是她干的
That vandalism at the stockyard? Totally her.
我自己怎么可能对付的了牛啊
Like I could tip a cow by myself.
韦德，把你妈妈的拖拉机扔到 鱼塘里
Wade, isn't there some outstanding warrant
这事儿难道有许可证吗？
for whoever dumped your momma's tractor in the fish pond?
鸽子湾 警长办公室
I have ten of these, then it's gone.
如果你喜欢这个怪物…
So if you are loving this monster...
有多少？
How many?
我们只有八个了 我要是会用意大利语说，我就说了
Eight? We have eight only?
可我不会
If I could say that in Italian, I would.
九点一刻？真的啊
9: 1 5? Honestly!
这时候谁会来电话？
Who could be calling at this hour?
喂？喂？
Hello? Hello?
嗨，妈妈
Hey, Momma.
梅兰妮，是你吗？
Melanie, is that you?
这么晚了，你没事吧？
It's so late. Are you alright?
我…
I ...
我以为会给你个惊喜呢
I thought I'd surprise you.
接到你的电话 的确是个惊喜
This certainly is a surprise, hearing from you,
你现在是大忙人了
you being such a busy girl an' all.
我总是在洗盘子剥豆角的时候 给人打电话
I call people while I'm doing the dishes or shelling peas.
奥普拉说这是多重任务处理
- Oprah calls it multitasking. - Momma,
打电话不是惊喜 我回到镇里了
the call isn't the surprise. I'm in town.
我的天啊！
Lord love a duck!
我的小姑娘终于回家了 厄尔，她回来了
My baby girl has finally come home. Earl, she's in town.
你要是每句话都重复一遍的话 就不用坐在我椅子上了
If you're gonna repeat everything she says, get off my chair.
我就坐在这里，怎么着
- Momma... - I'm just sitting here.
- 声音怎么了？ - 我调小了
What happened to the sound?
- 这样我能听见 - 什么，你有千里眼吗？
I turned it down to hear the phone ring. Are you clairvoyant now?
声音太大了 我自己的声音都听不到了
It was so loud, I couldn't hear myself think.
I heard it at Joe and Merlene's house.
我只有三分钟
- Hello? - I only get three minutes.
你不用打电话 直接过来吧
You didn't need to call. Just come on by.
问题是我想让 爸爸来接我回家
Well, that's the thing. I was hoping Daddy could come and get me.
这次你又是因为什么而进去的？
So, what put you in jail this time?
都是因为杰克乱说话 就是个误会
Jake and his big fat mouth. It was just a misunderstanding.
就像那个我花钱办的婚礼一样
Like that wedding I paid for.
- 我管那个不叫婚礼 - 那个男孩很紧张
I would hardly call that a wedding. The boy was nervous.
他还带着前一晚的宿醉
He was still drunk from the night before.
- 你能指责他吗？ - 我能
- Can you blame him? - Yes, I can!
我自己去服务台 婚纱上还满是呕吐物
I went to the reception with puke down my dress
而他已经蒙头大睡 你还站在他那一边…
while he slept it off in the Travelodge.
我哪边都不站
- You're still siding with that... - I'm not siding with anybody.
- 那个男孩变了… - 我们可以不谈杰克吗？
- The boy's changed. - Can we not talk about Jake?
他是你不曾拥有过的儿子 我却是你唯一的女儿
I know he's the son you never had but I'm your daughter.
也许你想知道 关于我的新消息
Maybe you want to know what's new with me.
好啊，说吧
OK. Shoot.
我遇见了一个人
I met somebody.
他很不错
And he's quite a catch.
是个很棒的人
He's really a great guy.
我很开心
And I'm happy.
真的
Really.
到妈妈这里来，宝贝
Come to Momma, sugar.
嗨，妈妈
Hey, Momma.
我的天啊 看看你都瘦成皮包骨了
Good land of the living, you are skin and bones.
不给我微笑一下吗？ 你总还会微笑吧
Don't I get a smile? I know you got one in there.
咱们还是进去说吧
Let's not let all the bought air out.
你饿不饿？ 要不要吃点儿炸鸡排？
Well, are you hungry? You want me to reheat some chicken fried steak?
不用，妈妈，我不饿
- No, I'm fine. - Sweetie, you look tired
你看起来很累 你累不累？ 也许是因为你发型的问题
Are you tired? Maybe it's the way you're wearing your hair now.
你们把家里收拾得不错啊
You've done a lot with the place.
你听她的口音
Lord, listen to that accent.
来坐在我的宝贝椅子上 是前年圣诞节的礼物
Sit in my good chair. Your momma got me this Christmas before last.
你们本该去我那里的那一年？
When you were supposed to visit me?
我跟你说过好多次 不合适
I told you time and time again, it just didn't suit.
我拿机票给你看看
Let me get you those tickets.
坐下来
Sit down in it. Sit down.
看看这个
Now watch this.
不是很值吗？
I mean, isn't that quite the deal?
真是没话说 我怎么起来？
There are hardly words. How do I get out?
Oh, my God!
杰克说过 他想要一个吗？
Jake tell you he's thinking of getting one?
我明白你的顺序了 杰克、监狱，然后才是家
I see your priorities. Jake, jail and then home.
只是有些事情没办完
It was just unfinished business.
杰克做得很好 这个男孩成功了
Jake's doing alright. Boy's going places.
你也成功了 给你机票
Once upon a time you were going places too. Here are your tickets.
这是礼物 我宁愿你们用掉它们
These were a gift. I'd rather you guys just use them.
我不明白为什么 你们可以去参观美国所有的战场
I don't understand how you visit every stupid battlefield in the US
却不肯去你们唯一女儿的家里
but you can't manage to visit your daughter.
事情都有两方面，宝贝
The door swings both ways.
别跟我谈这些 我不懂
Don't get me started on things I don't understand.
就是这样
Here we go.
你想让我离开
You wanted me to get away and be somebody.
你推我去参加 州内的每场丽人游行
You shoved me in beauty pageants.
我只是说
- I'm just saying, is all. - What are you trying to say?
你想说什么？ 我怎么做你才会开心？
Tell me what I can do to make you happy.
你自己开心就好
- Just make yourself happy.
好了，就说到这里，好不好？
- Done. We're there, alright?
我现在是名人，有事业 人们希望能像我这样
I've made something of myself. I have a career. People want to be me.
有人爱我，我也爱他
And somebody loves me and I love him.
珀尔，你去冰箱里给我们 拿点儿蛋糕来吧
Pearl, get us some of that baloney cake out of the icebox.
你妈妈是个性格复杂的女人
Your momma's a complex woman.
我去睡了
I'm going to bed.
晚安，亲爱的
Goodnight, darling.
你对她一无所知 你连她是谁都不确定吧？
You know nothing about her. Are you even sure who she is?
我爱她，妈妈
I love her, Mom.
很好，但要小心 我们完全不同
That's nice. But be careful. You and I are different.
我们没有好坏之分 只是不同而已
Not better, not worse, just different.
我们要过公众生活 要给大家树立好榜样
We're in public life to serve, so we have to set good examples.
你一定要掌控一切吗？
Must you control everything?
六月份第二个周末 我会主持广场仪式
Tell her I reserved the Plaza for the second weekend in June.
你们可以有个漫长的订婚期
That should give you a nice, long engagement.
我们打算去爱尔兰过圣诞节
We were thinking Christmas in Ireland.
如果你觉得我会任凭一个女孩 说服你…
If you think I won't let some girl talk you into getting married. . .
她不是“一个女孩” 她是我的未婚妻
She is not "some girl". She's my fiancée, for Christ's sake.
你和你父亲一模一样
You are just like your father.
前一分钟你还聪明 自控，坚定不移
One minute, you're brilliant, controlled, steadfast.
下一分钟就会为了某个女人 把这些都抛开
The next, you're throwing it away on some piece of ass.
这是你的问题，妈妈 不是我的
Those are your issues, Mother, not mine.
好吧
OK.
别挂
Hold on.
你知道吗？
You know what?
离婚诉讼需要多长时间？
How long does a contested divorce take?
十八个月？
1 8 months?
布福德先生，我可没有十八个月 我连十八天都没有
Mr. Buford, I don't have 1 8 months. I don't have 1 8 days.
这不适合我
That's just not going to work for me.
Yeah. Yes.
这里可少见你这样的人
Don't see the likes of you round these here parts.
布福德先生…
Mr. Buford. . .
你的装束看起来就像 蒙大拿州弗雷德里克跳舞的女人
You look like sex on a stick. I have to call you back.
听着，你为什么不来亲我的…
Listen, why don't you just kiss my.. .
屁股！噢，天啊！
. .ass! Oh, my God.
那就上车，小姐 我可不能在大街上那么干
Get in the truck cos I don't do that sort of thing on the street.
看来你妈妈把你教得不错
Your momma raised you right.
这是什么？CK牌子的？ 真不错
What is that, Calvin Klein? Very nice.
我可不想让你妻子误会 给你添麻烦
Very good. I better back off. I don't want to get you in trouble with the little lady.
你有妻子吗？
There is a little lady?
我可养活不起 一个长期需要维护的姑娘
I can't afford me, much less some high-maintenance babe.
辛迪呢？ 你们在高中打得火热
What about Cindy? You were hot and heavy in high school.
她现在是纳什维尔的女子 垒球教练
She's a women's softball coach in Nashville.
怪不得当时玩接吻游戏呢
That explains some questions I had about a game of post office we played.
不会吧！
No!
我猜我们都有自己的小秘密 对不对？
I guess we all have our secrets, Bobby Ray.
是啊，我们都有
Yeah, we sure do.
我在网上看到你的消息了
But I read about yours on the internet.
What?
我知道你的全部情况
I know about the cocks in your henhouse.
博比雷，你很知道 怎么让女孩子害羞
God! Bobby Ray! You sure know how to make a girl blush.
我得回去了 你会呆一会吧？
I gotta get back. Are you in town for a while?
希望不要 我正要去抢银行呢
I hope not. I'm just hitting the bank.
- 我最好快跑！ - 很有趣
- I better scram. - Very funny.
- 看到你真好 - 我也是，再见
- It was good to see you. - Good to see you, too. Bye.
嗨，尤金，你的腿怎么样了？
Hi, Eugene. How's your leg?
没给我找太多麻烦 梅兰妮小姐
It don't give me too much trouble, Miss Melanie.
多萝西娅，我去拿午饭
Dorothea, I'm going to take my lunch.
哦，看看谁来了
Look what the cat dragged in.
多萝西娅？
Dorothea? My God, you've. . .
- 噢，天啊！你… - 减掉了五十公斤，我知道
. .lost 1 1 0lbs, I know.
- 恭喜 - 谢谢
Well, congratulations. Thanks.
- 你这里没有自动柜员机 - 那个东西？
You don't have an ATM. Them things. Russ won't get one
拉斯不想摆那个东西 这样会失去和顾客交流的机会的
because you lose personal contact with customers.
是啊，那样不好
Yes. That would be tragic.
韦德说你和杰克 破镜重圆了
Wade said you and Jake had quite the reunion.
但那只是枕边话
But that's just pillow talk.
- 你和韦德… - 在一起三年了
- Are you and Wade...? - Going on three years.
当然这不是蒂芙尼的
It ain't Tiffany's.
但是说回来，电视上听的 可不能全信
But then you can't believe everything on TV.
我要取点儿钱 从我的…
I need a withdrawal from my. . .
- 联合账户？ - 我的什么？
- . .joint account? - My what?
你的联合账户，和杰克一起的
Your joint account. With Jake.
据我听说的，你们还是夫妻
From what I hear, y'all are still married.
哦，是啊
Why, yes.
是的，我们还是
Yes, we are.
嗨，宝贝！
Hi, honey.
看起来不错啊 家人好吗？
Looking good. How's the family?
少废话，我的东西在哪里？
Cut the shit. Where's my stuff?
要是我不跟着你收拾 我算是什么妻子呢？
What kind of wife doesn't pick up after her husband?
算是不住在这里的妻子
The kind that don't live here.
我最后问你一次 我的备用钥匙呢？
I'm going to ask you one last time. Where is the hide-a-key?
我和韦德的妈妈就她的拖拉机 进行了一次最甜蜜的谈话
I had the sweetest chat with Wade's mom about her tractor.
你的口音变回来了，真不错
Nice to see you got your accent back.
我今天偶然发现了几件事
I stumbled across a few things today.
天啊！炉子怎么了？
Holy shit! What happened to the stove?
我在上面放的几个小磁铁 哪里去了？
And where are them magnets I had over here?
这是什么？鸡食吗？
What the hell is this? Chick food?
清淡啤酒，低卡路里含量
Lite beer. Less calories.
我想要张新床 可你最近去过床垫商店吗？
I tried to get a new bed but have you been to the Sit 'n Sleep lately?
我得从纽约订些东西
I'll have to order something from New York.
随便你怎么折腾 你都是花自己的钱
Whatever blows your dress up, darlin'. Go ahead and spend your money.
但是亲爱的，你说过 我们应该认为它是…
But, darlin', I thought you said we should think of
我们的钱
it as our money.
我知道刚刚你头脑中 闪过了“联合支票账户”这个词
Just a guess but I think the words "joint chequing" are flashing in your head right now.
你取了多少？
- How much did you take? - All of it.
- 全部 - 你这个不要脸的女人！
Son of a bitch!
你想要个妻子，就有个妻子
You want a wife, you got a wife!
你拿那么多现金干什么？ 你为什么不拿来投资？
Why do you have all that cash? Why don't you invest it?
离开这里
If you don't get out. . .
在文件上签字，我就还给你
Sign the papers and I'll give it back.
很好，给我笔
- Fine! - Fine. Give me the pen.
等会儿，你把那么多现金 存起来准备干什么？
- Why do you have all that cash? - Give me the pen.
你什么时候关了工厂？ 你在干什么违法的事儿吗？
When did you quit the tyre factory? Are you doing anything illegal?
也许我干了 我没有干涉你交男朋友
Maybe I am. So? I don't ask about your boyfriend.
你也别管我的生活
Keep your nose out of my life. Deal?
谁告诉你的？
Who told you?
宝贝，我说话慢 不代表我笨
Honey, just cos I talk slow doesn't mean I'm stupid.
听着，杰克…
Look, Jake. . .
没有人能在10岁的时候 就找到自己的灵魂伴侣
Nobody finds their soul mate when they're ten years old.
我想是的
Yeah, I guess.
这有什么意思呢？
I mean, where's the fun in that, right?
真不敢相信你这么多年 还保留着这个
I can't believe you kept this all these years.
大多数人都不知道 闪电击中的沙地是什么样的
Most people don't know lightning does that to sand.
嗨，梅兰妮，你知道吗？
Mel, you know what?
我还记得我有个重要的约会
I just remembered I got myself a hot date.
我得让我的律师看看这个
Mind if my lawyer looks at these?
算了吧 我只是个普通的乡下小子
- What? - Hell. I'm just a simple country boy.
这些词我都发不好音
There's words in there I can't even pronounce.
你可以拿走我的全部财产
You might be taking me to the cleaner's.
- 财产？你有吗？ - 这个花了多少钱？
- The cleaner's? You? - What'd this set you back?
比你一个月挣的还多 快在文件上签名！
More than you make in a month. Sign the damn papers!
不行，但是…
Nah, but
多谢你顺路来访
thanks for stopping by.
我爱你，我爱你，我爱你
- I love you, I love you, I love you. - Are you sitting down?
- 你坐着吗？ - 怎么啦？有坏消息？
Why? Bad news?
我刚刚拿起 《纽约杂志周刊》
I picked up New York magazine. And I quote,
时装周上的新气象
"That cool breath of fresh air at Fashion Week
就是即将嫁作人妇的 梅兰妮卡迈克尔
was the soon-to-be household name of Melanie Carmichael."
“业内人士将她称为 下一个巨星”
"Fashion insiders have labeled her the next big one."
噢，天啊！下一个巨星？
Oh, my God! The next big one?
宝贝，我需要这个 就像我需要你一样
God, honey, I needed that almost as much as I need you.
那是什么声音？
What is that noise?
我过去的声音
- The sound of my past.
好好享受吧
- Have fun.
好，再见
OK, bye.
和解吧！
Batten down the hatches, boys!
我最喜欢的儿媳妇 偏偏是个麻烦
Trouble just walked in, disguised as my favourite daughter-in-law.
她带着甜美的面容走进来 拥抱我
Drive that pretty face over here and give me a hug.
很快就是前儿媳妇了
Soon to be ex-daughter-in-law.
- 那个幸运的家伙是谁？ - 安德鲁
- Who's the lucky guy? - His name is Andrew.
是政界的
- He's in politics.
哦，我会投他一票
- He's got my vote.
见到你真好，小姑娘
Good to see you, baby girl.
好好招待这位女士 回头见
Give this lady whatever she wants! I'll catch up with you later.
我要一杯灰雁马丁尼 两个橄榄，大杯的，谢谢
I'll have a Grey Goose martini, two olives, dirty.
噢，天啊，梅兰妮？
Oh, my God! Melanie!
- 乐兰？ - 是我！
- Lurlynn? - Yes! Oh, my God!
噢，天啊！看看你 真奇妙啊
Look at you, all fancy,
你就像刚从杂志上走下来一样
like you stepped out of a magazine.
哦，谢谢，看看你啊
Well, thank you. Look at you.
你带着孩子，来酒吧
You have a baby. In a bar.
家里还有三个呢 这个还没断奶
Hell, I got three more at home. This one's still on the tit, so I can cart him anywhere.
是啊
Right.
我那天也差点买这件上衣
I almost bought that exact same top the other day.
可克林顿会杀了我的 要是我花30块钱买这件…
But Clinton would kill me if I spent 30 bucks on
毛衣
a sweater thing.
那个贾克琳史密斯 很清楚自己做的事情
That Jaclyn Smith knows what she's doing.
实际上，这是我的
Actually, it's mine.
波道夫采用了我的设计
Bergdorf just picked it up.
我现在设计衣服
I design clothes now.
你不说我还忘了 我好像听说过
Now that you mention it, I'm pretty sure I heard that.
那你认识贾克琳史密斯吗？
So, do you know Jaclyn Smith?
介意我也玩吗？
Mind if I join you?
说真的，我们介意
- Actually, we do. - You must be Jake's hot date.
- 这么说你就是杰克的重要约会 - 我是斯塔尔
I'm Starr.
梅兰妮，杰克的下贱老婆 他不愿跟我离婚
I'm Melanie, Jake's snotty Yankee bitch wife,
尽管我已经和别人 订婚了
whom he won't divorce, even though I'm engaged.
天啊！ 杰克，看看这个有多大！
Hot dog, Jake, look at the size of that thing!
亲爱的？干吗不去给我们 拿点儿喝的呢？
Honey, why don't you get us a couple of drinks?
OK.
你拿的是马丁尼？
Is that a martini?
不是我和她，我们 我和你，我们
Not me and her "us", you and I "us".
你干吗让我对你这么重要呢？
Why do you make me be mean to you?
你想在你的朋友面前丢脸吗？
Do you want to be humiliated in front of all your friends?
行了，梅兰妮 我们也是你的朋友
Come on, Mel. We were your friends too.
哦，看，看他啊
- Well, lookee, lookee, lookee. - Hot damn!
哦，这不是启示录里的 那两个伴郎吗？
Well, well, well. If it isn't the two groomsmen of the apocalypse.
嗨，埃尔登
Hey, Eldon. Are you hungry?
- 你饿不饿？ - 当然饿了
I'm starving, Clinton.
不要！你怎么敢这样！
No, don't you dare!
当然可以享用一下 梅兰妮三明治！
I could use a Melanie sandwich!
- 就像过去一样 - 别碰我！
- Just like old times. - Get your hands off me!
不，不像过去了，对吗？ 时间改变了一切
No! Not like old times, alright? Times have changed.
没有梅兰妮三明治 梅兰妮烟草
No more Melanie sandwich, no more Melanie taco,
没有梅兰妮玉米热狗了！
and no more Melanie corndog.
- 没错 - 只是和你玩玩
- Sure. - We're just playing.
拿起球杆来 我们来打桌球吧
Guys, let's play some pool.
如果你找不到 就用那根戳过她屁股的
You can't find a cue, just pull the one shoved up her ass.
我不敢相信 你还戴着这个傻帽子
I can't believe you still wear that same stupid hat.
我正要毁了它呢
Well, I just about got it broken in.
你给我老实坐好 看我怎么教训杰克
Now, sit your bony ass down
让他输惨一次
and watch me teach Jake here how to lose at pool.
看到吗，就是这样
That's the thing.
我不是那种会看的女孩 对吗，杰克？
I'm not really a watch-and-see kind of girl, am I, Jake?
现在好了，博比雷 你赢了
Come on, Bobby Ray, you got it.
博比雷？
Bobby Ray. . .
别动这个，好吗？
Don't blow this one, OK? Alright, baby?
你可以把那个女孩 从下等酒馆带走
You can take the girl out of the honky tonk
但是你却不能把下等酒馆 从女孩心里抹去
but you can't take the honky tonk out of the girl.
所以，杰克
So, Jake
你愿意和这个女孩离婚 还是想怎么样？
are you going to divorce this girl or what?
她等了七年 再等几天会要了她的命
Well, she waited seven years. A couple more days won't kill her. Unfortunately.
- 真是不幸啊 - 这也没什么不同
- Like it'll make a difference. - You never know.
你永远不会知道 你的杰克在这里…
You might be interested to know that Jake...
她愿意怎么想就怎么想吧
Let her think what she wants.
她很早以前就给我下了结论了
She made up her mind about me a long time ago.
某些东西永远不会改变
Some things never change.
就像这里的埃尔登
Like Eldon here.
他永远也不能把球 打进正确的球袋
He never could get his balls in the right pocket.
行了，杰克 说你和梅兰妮的事
OK, Jake. It's you and Mel.
就像州赛决赛一样 我们落后六分，还有七秒钟
Clutch time. Just like state playoffs. We're down by six. Seven seconds to go.
我们需要来个 漂亮的52码轰炸！
We need that beautiful 52-yard bomb!
你还记得吗，梅兰妮？
- Remember that, Mel?
怎么能忘呢？
- How could I forget?
就是那个晚上 杰克让我怀孕了
That was the night Jake got me pregnant.
这事你为什么不说出来呢？
Why don't you just go public with that shit?
这里没人能保守秘密
Come on. It's not like anybody can keep a secret here.
除了博比雷
- Except for Bobby Ray.
我对你做过什么？
- Now, what did I ever do to you?
你什么都没做过 也没对镇子里的其他女孩做过什么
You never did anything to me, darling. Or any other girl in town.
梅兰妮，你这是怎么了？
Melanie, what is wrong with you?
- 你什么意思？ - 她只是不开心
- What do you mean? - She's just unhappy.
如果我被人叫做“中等偏下” 我也会不开心
I would be too if Women's Wear Daily called me "less than mediocre".
你为什么不去同性恋酒吧？
Why don't you go to a gay bar?
博比雷去同性恋酒吧干什么？
Now what would B Ray do in a gay bar?
Well. . .
我今晚玩够了
I've had enough fun for one night.
得了，我开玩笑的
Come on, I was just kidding.
斯特拉！和我这些朋友再喝 一轮怎么样？
Stella! How about another round of drinks for my friends here?
我看你喝得够多了
Honey, you've had enough.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我觉得你是对的
I think you're right.
我受够了
I have had enough.
你们怎么能这样生活？
I mean, how do you people live like this?
好了
That's it, that's it.
你们知道外面有个很大的世界
Did you know there's a world out there
有很多除了猪肠、孩子和啤酒 之外的东西吗？
that has nothing to do with chitlins and children or beer?
她发疯的时候我更喜欢 杰克！
I liked her better when she was crazy. Jake.
你待他们如粪土
Why do you treat them like something you stepped in?
这是你自找的
- You asked for it! - I asked for it?
你偷了我的钱 把我家乱搞一通
You show up, steal my money then insult my friends,
然后来侮辱我朋友 装得一副比他们优秀的样子
acting like you're better than them!
我是比他们优秀！ 你还偷了我的笔
I am better than them! And you stole my pen.
你只关心那些事情
- That's all that matters to you. - Thank you.
钱、名牌、鞋子 你真可悲
The money, the labels, the shoes. You're pathetic!
你就有成就了吗？ 我要走了，就等我找到钥匙
Like you're going places. I am, as soon as I get my keys.
- 你不能开车 - 把皮包还我！
- No, you don't. - Give me my purse!
你想死就到别处去死
You want to kill yourself, you do it somewhere else. There.
至少我还有丰富的人生 既然你不能玩球了
At least I'm doing something. So what if you can't play football?
追寻新的梦想啊，我就是 好了吧！
- Get a new dream. I did. - Get in the truck now. Alright!
我想约会结束了吧？
I guess the date's over?
帮我个忙，开车跟着我们
Do me a favour. Follow us home.
晚上好，厄尔
Evening, Earl.
晚上好，杰克
Evening, Jake.
- 珀尔 - 杰克
- Pearl. - Jake.
珀尔，对她好一点 我可不想再失去她七年
Listen, Pearl, go easy on her. We don't want another seven years.
我们还在想何时会见到你呢
We were wondering when we'd see you.
天啊，爸爸 我要怎么向纽约市解释你的行为？
Christ Almighty, Daddy, how will I explain you in New York City?
历史就是历史 用不着掩盖它
History's history. No use sweeping it under the rug.
- 祝我好运吧 - 打垮北方佬
- Wish me luck. - Go get them Yankees.
这里真该有签证的入境管制的
People need a passport to come down here.
嗨，布赖恩特 他人呢？
Bryant, where is he?
Come here. Come on.
Come on. Bryant, come on.
她来这里干嘛？
What's she doing here?
我以为你走了
I thought you'd be gone.
我把钱存回去了
I put the money back.
谢了，让我不至于跳票
Thanks. Saves me from bouncing a lot of cheques.
它会游泳吗？
Can he swim?
看来不像会
Doesn't look like it.
我喜欢你做的一切
I like what you did, though.
装潢房子，那有助于我卖房子
To the house. Should help it sell quicker.
你要搬家？
Are you moving?
我在塔斯卡卢萨 花了很多时间，因此……
Well, I've been spending a lot of my time in Tuscaloosa, so...
这水有多深？
- How deep is that water?
大约两米半
- About eight feet.
听着，梅兰妮
Look, Mel,
我签了协议书
I signed your papers.
杰克，我无意伤害你或任何人
I never meant to hurt you or anybody else for that matter.
我只是来这里跟你说声
I just came out here to say
谢谢你
thank you.
你最好走开一点
You might want to move out of the way.
你不能就这样走掉！
You can't just leave!
我当然可以
Sure I can.
想来吗？
- You want to come?
去哪？
- Where are you going?
我有东西要给你看
I want to show you something.
我不行
- I can't.
是不行还是不想？
- Can't or won't?
都有
Both.
- 我以前认识的那个女孩啥都不怕 - 那女孩没有人生
The girl I knew used to be fearless. The girl you knew didn't have a life.
那你最好继续过你的日子吧 来吧，布赖恩特
You better get on with it then. Come on, Bryant.
来，上去
Come on, boy, get in here.
你知道博比雷贝利的住址吗？
Do you know Bobby Ray Bailey's address?
拉斐特街813号
81 3 Lafayette.
你不记得我了？
You don't remember me.
我当然记得你 你曾到过我池塘里偷鲶鱼
I remember you just fine. You used to steal catfish from my pond.
没错，我是偷过
Yes, sir. I did that.
对不起
I'm sorry.
在周末 博比雷会去卡迈克尔农庄
On weekends, Bobby Ray goes to the Carmichael plantation.
跟墨菲上校一起去 现在是观光季节
Visits with Colonel Murphy, it being tourist season.
Thank you.
- 什么事？ - 你好，我是梅兰妮…
- Yes? - Hi. I'm Melanie Carmi. . .
梅兰妮斯穆特，我来找博比雷的
Melanie Smooter. I'm here to see Bobby Ray.
他若没死就在后院，跟我来吧
If he's alive, he's out back. Come on.
他们在这附近，小心脚下
They're out here somewhere. Watch your step.
- 博比雷？ - 梅兰妮！
Bobby Ray?
别动！
Melanie? Don't move!
该死！
Hot damn!
别开火，长官，我马上回来
Hold your fire, sir.
我们不是瞄准你
We weren't aiming for you
但我想我不会参加你的丧礼
but I doubt I'd have gone to your funeral.
我不怪你
I guess I wouldn't blame you.
我都忘了这地方有多美了
I'd forgotten how beautiful this place was.
忘记事情真容易
It doesn't take much to forget things, does it?
不是那样的
- Bobby Ray, it's not like that.
我告诉你事情是怎样
- I'll tell you what it's not like.
你抛弃的不是只有杰克而已
It's not like Jake's the only one you run out on.
抱歉，我出卖了你
I'm so sorry I outed you.
我以为我若把焦点转到你身上
I guess I figured if I was pointing at you then.. .
就不会有人看穿我
. .nobody would see through me.
博比雷！我找不到引信！
Bobby Ray! I can't find the fuse!
我得趁他搞死自己前回去
I should go before he kills himself.
再见
Bye.
- 午安 - 有何贵干？
Afternoon. Can I help you?
我是《纽约邮报》的巴里洛温斯坦
Barry Lowenstein, New York Post.
很高兴见到你
Oh, boy. Am I glad to see you.
这里真是个截然不同的世界
I'll tell you, it's definitely another world down here.
你是邮报记者？
- Did you say the Post? - Yes.
对，我想访问你跟你的家人
I was hoping to interview you and your family.
照一些相，若你不介意的话
Maybe a few pictures, if you don't mind.
不，我是说，我介意
No. I mean, yes, I do. Mind.
他们不在
They're not here.
这里跟你形容的一样
This is just as you described it.
在这里长大一定很有趣
It must have been amazing growing up here.
就像童话一样
Like a fantasy.
- 我能看一下里面吗？ - 我正要出门
- Could I take a quick look inside? - I'm on my way out.
我晚一点再过来
- I'll come back then.
好吧，看一下就好
- OK, but just a peek.
这就是了，甜蜜的家
This is it. Home, sweet home.
这里有多少年历史了？
How old is this place?
这是我…曾曾曾祖父
It was built by my great-great-great-grandfather.
查尔斯卡迈克尔在1853年建的
Charles Carmichael, in 1 853.
我敢说你一定滑过栏杆
Boy. I bet you slid down this bannister a time or two.
这里是我们的…
And over here, we have the...
厨房，没啥好看的，这边来
. .kitchen. But who hasn't seen one of those? Over here.
这是我最喜欢的房间
This is my favourite room.
这是…秘密通道的一部分
It was part of the... Underground Railroad.
我们为何要小声说话？
Why are we whispering?
这整个地方都…
The whole place is haunted.
闹鬼
By ghosts of...
南北战争士兵的鬼魂
. .Civil War soldiers.
讨厌的南军军服钮扣
Dang Confederate buttons!
难怪我们会打输
No wonder we lost the war.
那是不是其中一个鬼魂？
Was that one of them?
梅兰妮？
Melanie?
你在衣橱里干嘛？
- What are you doing in the closet?
《纽约邮报》的巴里洛温斯坦
- Barry Lowenstein, New York Post.
卡迈克尔小姐在带我参观农庄
Miss Carmichael was showing me around the plantation.
洛温斯坦先生想访问我家人
Mr Lowenstein is writing a piece on the family,
因为我要嫁给市长的公子
since I'm marrying the mayor's son and all.
我不知道，那很重要吗？
I had no idea. Isn't that something?
Yeah.
农庄其实只是个农场
A plantation by any other name is just a farm.
只是名称好听了些
But it does roll off the tongue a little sweeter.
梅兰妮忘了礼貌 我是博比雷
Miss Melanie forgot her manners. I'm Bobby Ray.
她表哥
Her cousin.
幸会
Charmed.
北方佬到阿拉巴马时
The Yankees tried to destroy our metal-forming capabilities
就在铁砧下放炸药
by placing barrels of powder underneath the anvils.
结果他们只是把铁砧轰上天
All they managed to do was blow 'em sky-high for a few seconds.
为了表彰这种愚蠢行为
In honour of that act of stupidity,
我们为观光客重现原景
we recreate it for the tourists.
那是什么东西？
What the hell was that?
爷爷！这是巴里 他在为梅兰妮的婚礼写文章
Grandpa! This here's Barry. He's doing an article on Melanie's wedding.
没听说过她！
Never heard of her!
谢了！
Thanks!
你真是够能编啊！
Well, aren't you just a big fat liar?
博比雷！
- Bobby Ray!
回去纽约吧
- Oh, go back to New York.
我对我说过的话感到抱歉
I'm sorry about what I said.
真的很对不起
- Really sorry. - Oh, well.. .
别提了
Forget it.
快吃，别说话 我们还要去拜访别人
OK, y'all. You need to eat and be quiet. We're gonna have us a visit.
你知道吗，他去过北方
You know, he went up there.
谁？杰克？什么时候？
Who? Jake? When?
你离开后一年
About a year after you left.
他不知道我知道，克林顿说溜嘴了
He don't know I know. But Clinton let it slip once.
杰克去纽约？
- Jake was in New York?
他说他没看过那样的世界
- He'd never seen anything like it.
他明白光道歉没办法赢回你的心
He realised straight off he'd need more than an apology to win you back.
他要先征服世界
He needed to conquer the world first.
之后他就一直在努力
He's been trying ever since.
所以他才一直退回协议书
That's why he kept sending the papers back.
是啊
Yeah.
世事总是不能尽如人意
It's funny how things don't work out.
有时也会如意幸福
It's funny how they do.
看我在停车场找到谁
Look who I found by the parking lot, hesitant to join us.
这里有什么东西会吓跑博比雷？
Anybody think of anything in here that might bother Bobby Ray?
克林顿的口臭？
Clinton's breath?
- 你还是原来的博比吧？ - 如假包换
- You still the same Bobby Ray? - Last time I checked, yeah.
那让我请你喝一杯吧
Well, then, let me buy you a drink.
你不是我喜欢的那型
You're really not my type.
喝东西要从上面喝
Honey, you drink that from the top.
我想知道“南方玻璃”是谁做的
I'm just looking to see who makes this Deep South Glass.
不知道纽约能不能买到，好漂亮
I wonder if you can get it in New York. It's beautiful.
嘿，杰克，梅兰妮想知道
Jake!
哪里能买到好玻璃
Mel wants to know where she can find some of that snooty-falooty glass.
- 干嘛问我？ - 也许是因为你…
- Why ask me? - I don't know. Maybe because you're. . .
你今天打扮得很帅
You're all spiffed up and all.
我是不是漏了什么？
Am I missing something?
我们表示点敬意吧，各位
Let's show some respect, folks.
杰克
Jake, when was the last time you pushed me around the dance floor?
你上次跟我跳舞是什么时候？ 克林顿的脚会打结
Clinton has got two left feet.
泰勒小姐，这是我的荣幸 来跳舞吧
Well, Miss Taylor, I'd be honoured. Let's do it.
梅兰妮，来跳舞吧！
Come on, Mel! Get out here!
你不是舞王吗？
Aren't you the Lord of the Dance?
我不像我的外表一样笨拙 是她老跟不上拍子
I ain't as clumsy as I look. She just can't keep time.
你得证明这点
You might have to prove that to me.
他很行，可能是你的问题
He's pretty good. It might be you.
你乱讲！我来跟他跳！
The hell you say! Let me at him.
看看他们俩，互相吸引
Look at them two, welded together.
他们干嘛要抗拒呢？
Why do they fight it?
也许我们聊聊天就好
Maybe we could just talk.
- 去酒吧吧 - 不了
Come on. Let's go to the roadhouse. Nah.
开车去费尔维尤打两局保龄球吧
Let's drive to Fairview and bowl a few frames.
- 我不想 - 要不要去逮捕什么人？
- I don't think so. - Want to go arrest somebody?
- 我知道一个很棒的地方… - 不要！
- I know this great place where.. . - No!
我要回家睡觉了
Y'all, I think I'm gonna call it a night.
猎犬墓园
熊熊
你好
Hey there, boy.
抱歉我来晚了
Sorry it took me so long.
要是我早知道你病了 我会早点回来
I'd have come sooner if I'd known you were sick.
其实，那可能也不是实话
Actually, that's probably not true.
我最近很自私
I've been pretty selfish lately.
狗是不懂自私的
Dogs don't know anything about that, do they, though?
你一直都像个舒服的大枕头
You were always like a big old pillow.
当情况不对时
When everything went pear-shaped...
你都会守在我身边
. .you never left my side.
但我却离开了你
And then I just left you.
你一定以为自己做错了什么
I bet you sat there wondering what you'd done wrong.
我跟它说是我的错
I told him it was my fault.
- 别再扮好人了 - 那是事实
- Quit being so nice. - It's the truth.
为什么要这么复杂？
Why does it have to be so complicated?
- 什么？ - 事实
- What? - The truth.
人生
Life.
这个
This.
它是只很棒的狗
He was one hell of a good dog.
是啊
Yeah.
你今晚似乎玩得很愉快
You looked like you were having fun tonight.
我在纽约很快乐，杰克
I'm happy in New York, Jake.
但当我回到这里
But then I come down here
这里却也能安慰我
and this fits too.
何必分得那么清楚呢？
Since when does it have to be one or the other?
你可以有根也有翅膀，梅兰妮
You can have roots and wings, Mel.
也许我能飞到南边过冬
Maybe I can just fly south for the winter.
你看
Look.
那里，看到了吗？
- What? - There. Can you see 'em?
荧火虫，只有你会注意
Lightning bugs. Only you.
我还是偶尔会到野外去
You know, I still go out there sometimes.
我看着那些雷雨云逼近
I see those big thunderheads rolling in.. .
这就像一种信仰
It's like a religion.
我之前做过那个梦
I had a dream about it the other night.
想过要是你没怀孕会怎样吗？
Ever wonder what would have happened if we hadn't got pregnant?
- 杰克 - 只是…
- Jake... - Let me
我想趁这个机会告诉你
get this out before I can't.
我认为生下小孩是个冒险
I thought that baby would be an adventure.
我花了好些时间后来才明白 那会是你必经的冒险
It took me a while to realise it would have been your only adventure.
生死天注定
I just guess Mother Nature knew better.
我很惭愧
I was so ashamed.
因为我是觉得
Cos I felt...
松了一口气
. .relieved.
而突然间
And all of a sudden,
我需要一个不一样的人生
I just needed a different life.
你做得真的很好
And you've done real well for yourself.
我很为你感到骄傲，梅兰妮
I'm proud of you, Mel.
很抱歉婚礼时没与你共舞
I'm just sorry I never danced with you at our wedding.
我相信你下一场婚礼一定会更棒
I'm sure this next one will go better for you.
杰克，我不能再谈了
Jake, I can't do this.
我知道
I know.
回家吧
Go home.
我只是说说而已
I'm just saying, is all.
我看到你们俩互相对望
I saw you two looking at each other.
我管不了杰克对我的感觉 他没做错什么
Momma, I can't help how Jake feels about me. He's done nothing wrong.
他也没做对什么啊
- He's done nothing right either. - Why are we having this argument?
我们为何要争执？ 我要嫁给别人
I'm leaving. I'm marrying another man.
没错，你有了第二次机会 别搞砸了
That's right, young lady. You get a second chance, so don't mess it up.
对谁而言？ 对我还是对你？
- For whom? For me or for you? - Don't sass me, OK?
别惹我，好吗？ 多年来我对你容忍不少
Don't you dare. I have put up with an awful lot from you over the years.
例如我没参加宝贵的选美比赛？
What? Like me quitting your precious pageants?
我不希望你跟我一样！该死的！
I didn't want you to end up like me! Damn it!
你要远离这里 那家伙是绊脚流沙
You need to stay far away from here. That boy is quicksand.
妈妈，跟你一样又怎么样？
What's so wrong with being you, Momma?
我只觉得你值得更好的人生
I just think that you deserve better, that's all.
我知道你值得的
I know you do.
你一直都值得
You always have.
纽约见了，好吗？
I'll see you in New York, alright?
你会喜欢那里的
You'll like it.
我保证
I promise.
别忘了跟你爸说再见
Don't forget to say goodbye
战场
to your daddy.
爸？
Daddy?
你在找谁，亲爱的？
Who you looking for, darling?
厄尔斯穆特
Earl Smooter.
第五军团的？
Fifth Regiment?
有人看见厄尔斯穆特吗？
Anybody seen Earl Smooter?
他正要去投降！
He's about to surrender!
谢谢！
Thank you!
你先请
After you.
午安
Good afternoon.
- 你好吗？ - 很好，谢谢，你呢？
- How are you? - Good, thanks. Yourself?
没啥好抱怨的
No complaints.
这房子真漂亮
- This is a beautiful house. - Sure.
你来找博比雷？
You here to see Bobby Ray?
其实我是来给梅兰妮惊喜的
Actually, I'm hoping to surprise Melanie.
- 梅兰妮？ - 我的未婚妻
- Melanie? - My fiancee.
你走错房子了吧？
You got the wrong house, don't you?
这里是卡迈克尔家，对吧？
This is the Carmichael place, isn't it?
我们谈的是同一个人吗？
Are we talking about the same girl?
- 梅兰妮斯穆特？ - 梅兰妮卡迈克尔
- Melanie Smooter? - Melanie Carmichael.
- 怪不得了 - 是啊
Well, that explains it. It sure does.
安德鲁亨宁斯
Andrew Hennings.
- 杰克佩里 - 幸会，杰克
- Jake Perry. - Nice meeting you, Jake.
嘿，杰克
Hey, Jake.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
我在跟梅兰妮的未婚夫聊
Oh, you know. Just talking to Mel's fiance here.
你知不知道她去哪了？
Wondering if you might know where she is.
- 安德鲁亨宁斯，你是… - 我是博比雷，她的…
Andrew Hennings. You must be...
表哥？
I'm Bobby Ray, her. . . cousin?
你见过杰克了，他是她…
- I see you've met Jake, her. . .
另一个表哥
- Her other cousin.
家人！能见到你们真好
Family. It's great to meet you both.
梅兰妮提过要去战场找她爸爸
Melanie said something about visiting her daddy up at the battlefield.
战场？
Battlefield?
在南方，南军战败的时刻 成了不朽的时刻
In the South, the minute the Confederacy died, it became immortal.
来吧，我…
Come on. I'll give you a ride up there.
我载你过去
That's great, thank you.
太好了，幸会了
Nice meeting you.
梅兰妮斯穆特是谁啊？
So, who's. . . Melanie Snooter?
- 地方上的英雄 - 为什么？
- Local hero round here. - Why's that?
她炸了银行
- She blew up the bank.
那就让她成了英雄？
- And that made her a hero?
她恶名昭彰，当时她才十岁
Well, notorious, anyway. She was ten.
还好没人受伤，除了一只猫
Fortunately, nobody was hurt, except maybe the cat.
- 什么猫？ - 那只背上被绑着炸药的猫
What cat? The one with the dynamite on its back.
- 她炸猫？ - 它反正是劫数难逃
- She blew up a cat? - He was scheduled to die anyway.
- 被炸死？ - 兽医说它得了癌症
- From dynamite? - The vet said it had cancer.
埃尔登想把它送进毒气室
So Eldon thought it'd be put in a chamber that sucks their lungs out.
梅兰妮受不了那个想法
Mel couldn't bear the thought of that.
她要更人道的做法
She wanted something more humane. Yeah, sure.
当时正在用炸药开新公路
They were blasting by the new highway,
所以我们抓小毛去，绑上炸药
so we took ol' Fuzz up there, taped him up.
为了安全起见 我们用了九米长的引线
We used about 30 feet of fuse, just to be safe.
- 祈祷之后就跑开了 - 当然
- Said our prayers and ran like hell. - Of course.
后来我们坐在小吃店 感觉很难过
So there we were, sitting in Virgie's diner, feeling pretty blue,
当梅兰妮看到那只猫跑出来
when Mel sees that cat trotting down the road, searching for Eldon.
不会吧
No shit.
当引线点着尾巴时，它抓狂
We'd have caught him but once that fuse hit his tail, he took off like a shot.
冲进银行？
And into the bank.
它显然甩开了炸药
He probably wriggled loose from the explosive
因为人们还是会看到它
cos people still see him, scorched tail and all.
尾巴烧焦，它有点容易受惊
He's a bit skittish round humans.
- 真特别的故事 - 她是很特别的女孩
- That's quite a story. - She was quite a girl.
她后来怎样了？
Whatever happened to her?
噢，你知道的
Oh, you know.. .
未婚怀孕 高中毕业后就嫁给了一个窝囊废
Wound up pregnant, married some loser right out of high school.
惊讶吗？
Surprised?
- 你在这里干嘛？ - 我送你未婚夫过来
- What are you doing here? - I came to deliver your fiance.
她是在问我
- I think she was talking to me. - Jake...
- 一定很累吧 - 什么？
Must be exhausting. - What? - What?
- 活在谎言之中 - 他说什么？
- Living a lie. - What is he talking about?
你我爱的是两个不同的人
You and I are in love with two different people.
他是你另一个表哥吗？
Is he a second cousin?
他是我丈夫
- He's my husband. - Your what?
- 你什么？ - 我是说…前夫
- My ex-husband. - You married your cousin?
- 你嫁给你表哥？ - 我是来离婚的
- I came to finalise my divorce. - Jesus Christ!
小乖，我就知道是你
Hey, darling. I thought that was you.
这一定是你的某人了
This must be your new someone.
厄尔斯穆特，幸会
Earl Smooter. Glad to meet you.
梅兰妮斯穆特
Melanie Smooter.
安德鲁，等等！
Andrew, wait! Wait!
I just. .. Please!
让我解释
Let me try and explain myself.
你不明白 这不只是我是谁的问题
You don't understand. This is not who I am any more.
我不知道你是谁 但我知道
I don't know who you are but I know one thing.
莫比尔有班机 我要搭机回去
There is a Lear jet in Mobile and I am on it.
我知道你认为我这回搞砸了
I know you're thinking I spoiled things good this time.
别为了我的想法指控我 我不做那种事
Don't go accusing me of thinking. I ain't doing anything of the sort.
旁观者的眼里也许是搞砸了
Anyway, spoiled is in the eye of the beholder.
就像这些梅子
Like these plums.
有些人会说它们都坏了
Some people might call them spoiled
但我却认为 这些快熟烂的梅子
but I think that these almost ruined ones
能做出最甜的果酱
sometimes make the sweetest jam.
你需要帮忙吗？
Do you need any help?
看到爸投降满好玩的
It was kind of fun seeing Daddy up there surrendering.
他的确有演戏的天赋
Yeah. He sure does have a flair for the dramatic.
我的家族就没这种遗传
You certainly don't get it from my side of the family.
看我在58号公路上找到谁了？
Hey, y'all, look who I found walking down 958.
Hi.
我以为你在回纽约的路上了
I thought you'd be halfway to New York by now.
我也这么想
So did I .
要是我知道会有客人 我就会好好摆一下门面
If I'd known company was coming, I'd have put on the dog.
这是我妈
This is my momma.
她做的果酱在临近三县最棒
She makes the best jam in three counties.
还有我爸，你见过他了
And my dad. You already met him.
这里则是我们的家
And this is our home.
这是我成长的地方
This is where I grew up.
很高兴能见到两位
It's a pleasure meeting you both.
我是安德鲁亨宁斯 梅兰妮的未婚夫
I'm Andrew Hennings, Melanie's fiance.
如果她还愿意嫁给我的话
Well, that is if she'll still have me.
听着，梅兰妮
Look, Mel,
我不在乎这里的过往
I really don't care what happened down here.
你有过去，谁没有呢？
So you have a past. I mean, who doesn't?
我想知道的是 你的未来有没有我的位置
What I need to know is if there is a place for me in your future.
噢，老天啊，真是太甜蜜了
Good Lord, that is the sweetest thing.
Go on.
纽约，我们来了
Hello, New York City.
女人，你在胡说什么？
Woman, what are you gassin' about?
伯父，我妈是那里的市长
Well, sir, my mother happens to be the mayor up there.
她喜欢办盛大的纽约婚礼
And she'd like nothing better than a big, snazzy New York wedding.
我想我可以休个假
Well. . . I suppose I could take off work.
安德鲁，我…
Andrew, I. . .
也许我们可以在这里办婚礼
I was thinking maybe we could have the wedding here.
- 这里？ - 在我的家乡
Here? In my hometown.
要是你担心钱的问题
If you're worried about the money. ..
不是钱的问题，安德鲁 这里不存在这个问题
It's not about the money, Andrew. Not down here.
很多人期望我们在城里结婚
A lot of people are expecting us to get married in the city.
但我想宁静的乡间婚礼正合适
But I think a nice quiet country wedding is just the ticket.
厄尔…
Earl,
珀尔，你们负责彩排晚宴就好
Pearl, if you folks could take care of the rehearsal dinner,
其它的我来负责
I'd really like to take care of the rest.
我想我们可以负责
I think we could cover that.
女儿一辈子能嫁几次呢？
Heck! How many times does your only daughter get married?
以前除外
Other than before.
- 罪犯梅兰妮？ - 她没犯过罪
- Felony Melanie? - She was never convicted.
“杀猫手”和“南军后裔”
Which is worse, child cat-killer or sons of the Confederacy?
你要我因为她穷就抛弃她？ 你是民主党员啊！
What do you suggest I do? Dump her for being poor? You're a Democrat, remember?
穷没什么不好 就是穷人选我出来
There's nothing wrong with being poor. I get elected by poor people.
我建议她努力一点
And I commend her for making something of herself.
但她对你说谎
I'm upset that she lied to you.
她对自己的出身感到羞愧
So what? She was ashamed of her background.
谁不为自己的出身感到羞愧？
Who isn't embarrassed by their parents at some point?
我觉得这是指控而不是疑问
I'll assume that's a rhetorical question.
随便你
Assume away.
没人能改变我的决定 任何人都不行
No one can change my mind about this. Not you, not the media, not anyone.
好吧
Fine.
但你要承认，我是对的
But admit it. I was right.
对，你是对的 我们可以继续下去了吧？
Yes, you were right. But she came clean. Can we move on?
不管你喜不喜欢，等着办婚礼吧
There is a wedding in your future, whether you like it or not.
阿拉巴马小姐 要怎么安排500人住宿？
And how does Miss Alabama plan to accommodate 500 people?
靠她跟监狱的交情？
She has connections at the jail?
那里有很多好地方
There are several excellent choices.
行者旅店、每日客栈、欢乐旅馆
The Travelodge, Days Inn, Motel 6
还有金莓旅社，我们就住那里
and the Golden Cherry Motel, where we will be.
- 笑吧，等媒体一知道… - 不会的
Laugh now. But if this gets out...
媒体以为六月才会举行
It won't. The press expects the Plaza in June.
先敬罗衣后敬人
关于你的婚礼
About your wedding.
这地方很棒 我们又能做好安全设施
This place is gorgeous and we can control the security.
卡迈克尔农庄？
The Carmichael plantation?
这的确点出了你的身分，对吧？
It did inspire your identity, did it not?
- 你想得真周到 - 我一直如此，保持联络
- You thought of everything. - I always do. Keep in touch.
我爱纽约 放活鸟
三次欢呼！ 包办宴会
记得那个酋长吗？
- You guys remember the sheik? - Yeah.
他向我求婚，我想我爱他 撇开他的万贯家财不谈
He proposed and I think I loved him, despite his billions.
你为何不答应？
Why didn't you say yes?
我发现我的理智和情感不一致
I realised my head and my heart were saying two different things.
这是个很重大的决定
It's a big decision.
这应该是你做过最简单的决定
It's supposed to be the easiest one you make.
不是吗？
Wasn't it?
塔芭塔，这就是我跟你提过的
Tabby, this is it! This is the stuff I was telling you about.
南方玻璃
"Deep South Glass."
对，去吧
Oh, yes. Let's.
吹玻璃
周末盛大开幕
噢，真漂亮
Oh, that's pretty.
- 怎么回事？ - 噢，老天啊
What's the matter? Oh, my God.
我们认识…
Do we know...
姓莫的吗？
. .Mo?
Mel?
你看看这些
Look at these.
那都是砂子，闪电打过就变这样
It's what happens to sand when it struck by lightning.
她在戏弄你
- She's pulling your dick. - No, really.
不，真的，我看过 你只需要把它挖起来
I've seen it. You just have to dig it up.
- 嘿，布赖恩特 - 你朋友？
- Hey, Bryant. - Friend of yours?
我先看到他的
I saw him first.
我想他已经心有所属了
I think he's already taken.
我一直想联络你
I ... I tried to call you a couple of times.
你跟你朋友该四处看看
You and your friends should look around and have some lunch.
吃个午饭 坐在甲板上，很不错的
Sit on the deck. It's nice.
杰克
Jake.
来吧，布赖恩特 别打扰这位小姐了
Come on, Bryant. Let's. . . Let's leave this lady alone.
Come on.
有事吗，先生？
Sir, can we help you?
我要找梅兰妮卡迈克尔
I'm looking for a Melanie Carmichael.
有人知道这名字吗？
Anybody here recognise that name?
你找她有什么事？
- What business you got with her?
这是私事
- I'm afraid that's a private matter.
那恐怕我们帮不上你的忙了
Then I'm afraid we can't help you.
- 该死的记者 - 就像野餐上的蚂蚁
Damn reporters. It's like the first ant at a picnic.
这是在路易斯安那买的
Now. This one here is from Louisiana.
上面还有只小鳄鱼
It's got a little alligator on top.
真可爱！ 怪不得梅兰妮这么有品味
How sweet. I can see where your daughter gets her taste.
等待真是一种折磨
This is one of those disasters waiting to happen.
只有蟑螂才能活得下来
One of the big ones only cockroaches survive.
不会有事的
It's going to be fine.
打死一只，还有七百万只要消灭
One down, seven million to go.
小心 你刚刚打死了阿拉巴马的州鸟
Careful. You just smashed the state bird of Alabama.
珀尔女士 终于见面了
Pearl. Well, finally.
怪不得梅兰妮这么可爱
Oh, my. Well, I can see why Melanie is so adorable.
我真高兴能来这里，嗨，厄尔
I'm so happy to be here. Hi, Earl.
我们很高兴你能来
We're so happy to have you here.
抱歉这一团乱 亨宁斯夫人，市长！
I'm sorry the place is such a mess, Mrs Hennings. Mayor!
不，不，不，叫凯特就好
No, no. It's Kate.
我一直想叫厄尔除草
I've been trying to get Earl to weed these shrubs and repaint the trim.. .
再重新漆过篱笆 老天，你看她真漂亮
Oh, my God! Look how pretty she is, Earl.
我想凯特想喝点东西
- I'll bet Kate could use a drink.
凯特的确想
- Kate could indeed.
进来吧 我煎了点酸黄瓜
Come right on then. I've got some fried pickles, hot out of the grease.
Yum.
这椅子真可爱，厄尔
It's a lovely chair, Earl.
要体验它的效果 你得拉这个把手
To get the full effect, you pull this handle here.
- 爸，不要 - 饮料拿稳了，凯特
Daddy, no! Hold onto your drink, Kate.
- 姓名？ - 华莱士布福德
- Name? - Wallace Buford.
我不在名单上 但我有重要的事找新娘
I'm not on that list but I've got some urgent business with the bride.
今天不行，来人
Not today, you don't. Trooper.
请掉转车头，快点
- Sir, let's get it turned around. - Let's go.
Hi.
今天有一场婚礼呢
- There's a wedding going on.
我听人说过了
- I heard a mention of it.
我希望天气合作
I sure hope this weather cooperates.
看来应该是个大风暴
It's supposed to be a big one.
杰克
You know, Jake,.. .
你是我唯一的儿子，我也爱你
. .you're my only son and I love you.
但有时你太像你父亲了
But sometimes you are too much like your daddy.
她做了决定，妈妈
She made her decision.
对于一个努力想挽回的人来说
For somebody who's been holding onto something so hard,
你太快就放手了
you're pretty quick to let it go.
我控制不了她 就跟我控制不了天气一样
I can't control her any more than I can control the weather.
你只是紧张，你做得很对
It's just nerves. You're doing the right thing.
是吗？
Am l?
当我嫁给你爸时…
When I married your daddy. . .
老天，我太迷恋他了
Lord, I was a fool for that man.
我连路都走不好
I couldn't put one foot in front of the other.
我记得我还在想 “快，趁他还没改变心意”
I remember thinking, "Preacher, hurry up before he changes his mind."
你看我今天是什么样子
Look where it got me.
有时那个人真让我抓狂 我真想掐死他
Sometimes that man makes me so mad, I could wring his neck.
- 但你还爱他吧？ - 天知道我爱
But you still love him?
也只有他知道原因
God knows I do. And only He knows why.
妈，我…
Momma...
他能给你我们想不到的人生
He can give you a life that we never dreamed of.
他也爱你
And he adores you.
他是爱我，不是吗？
He does, doesn't he?
虽然他是北方佬，至少他很清醒
Even if he is a Yankee, at least he's sober.
卡迈克尔小姐！
Miss Carmichael!
回来！
Get here! Get back here!
布福德先生？
Mr Buford? Get your hands off me!
- 放开我！ - 放开他！
Let him go!
梅兰妮？
Melanie?
你这女人真是难找
You are one hard woman to get in touch with.
他签字了，你还来这干嘛？
Mr Buford, he signed the papers. What are you doing here?
他是签了
He did.
但你没签
You didn't.
What?
女方签名
你是说，我还是已婚？
I'm still married?
如果你想要的话
Well, . . . only if you want to be.
梅兰妮，我以为你搞定了
For God's sakes, Melanie, I thought you took care of this.
这是个错误
It's an honest mistake.
那我们能在被淋湿前搞定吧？
Then can we fix it before we all get soaked?
有人有带笔吗？
Does anybody have a pen?
- 妈？ - 噢，是哦
- Mom? - Oh, yeah, sure.
亲爱的？
Darling?
这种事不会是意外
These things don't just happen, you know.
你不能脚踏两条船，小乖
You can't ride two horses with one ass, sugarbean.
安德鲁？
Andrew?
你不想娶我的
- You don't want to marry me. - I don't?
- 我不想？ - 你不想
No. No, you don't.
不是真的想
Not really.
事实是…
You see, the truth is. . .
我很久以前就爱上了别人
. . I gave my heart away long ago.
全心全意 而我一直无法收回我的心
My whole heart. And I never really got it back.
我不知道我还能说什么 但我很抱歉
I don't even know what else to say but I'm sorry.
我不能嫁给你
I can't marry you.
你也不该娶我
And you shouldn't want to marry me.
原来被甩就是这种感觉
So this is what this feels like.
就这样？
That's it?
你就这样让她 用她前任老公当借口羞辱你？
You're letting her humiliate you with some bullshit about an old husband?
对
Yeah.
我想我是
I think I am.
抱歉
Excuse me.
你…
You. . .
我这辈子
In my entire life,
从没见过这么会操纵别人 这么会骗人的人
I have never met anyone so manipulative, so deceitful.
我还在政界打滚呢！
And I'm in politics!
我是实话实说
I'm just being honest.
我不会让未来的美国总统
I will not allow the future president of the United States
在婚礼上被乡下村姑给甩了！
to be dumped at the altar by some psycho Daisy May!
快去追他，你这个贱人！
- You go after him, you little bitch!
等一等，小姐
- Wait. Just a minute, missy.
你不用侮辱人
There's no need for name calling.
她说了她该说的，就这么简单
She spoke her piece and that's all there is to it.
回你的破家煮菜去吧
Go back to your double wide and fry something.
没有人能对我妈这么说话
Nobody talks to my momma like that!
赞美上帝！ 南方人又起来了！
Praise the Lord! The South has risen again!
新娘的朋友们，别走开！ 我要去找新郎了！
Hey! Y'all! lf you're friends of the bride, stick around! I'm gonna go find me a groom!
嘿，牛仔！
Hey, cowboy!
你欠我一支舞
You owe me a dance.
真美的礼服，你老公呢？
Nice dress. Where's your husband?
我正在看着他
I'm looking at him.
显然，你跟我还是夫妻
Apparently, you and I are still hitched.
是吗？
- Is that right? - Yeah.
你为何不告诉我你到了纽约？
Why didn't you say you came to New York?
- 我得有所成就才行 - 你成功了吗？
- I had to make something of myself. - You about done?
南方女人是怎么回事？
What is it about Southern girls? Can't make the right decision
尝尽苦头还是下不了决定？
till you try all the wrong ones?
我为自己想要的东西在奋斗！
I fight for what I want!
你想要什么？ 我想连你都不清楚
What do you want? I don't even think you know.
你是我吻的第一个男生 我要你也是最后一个
You're the first boy I ever kissed, Jake. I want you to be the last.
也许我们试过了
Maybe you and I had our chance.
好！随便你，你这个老顽固！
Fine! Have it your way, you stubborn ass!
你为什么想嫁给我？
What do you want to be married to me for anyhow?
那样我就可以随时吻你
So I can kiss you anytime I want.
你们想自杀吗？
What the hell are you two trying to do? Get yourselves killed?
有什么问题吗？
What seems to be the trouble, Officer?
- 我是来逮捕你的 - 她这回又做了什么？
I'm here to bring you in, young lady. What'd she do this time?
我听说她丢下了一个完美的大蛋糕
Well, the way I hear it, it seems she ran out on a perfectly good cake!
Here we go.
看谁终于赶上自己的婚礼了
Well, folks. Look who finally made it to their reception.
各位，佩里先生和夫人！
Ladies and gentlemen, Mrs and Mr Jake Perry!
带着手铐去度蜜月吧
You might want to keep those for the honeymoon.
发言！发言！
Speech!
我相信我欠这位小姐一支舞
Well, I do believe I owe this lady a dance.
没错！
You sure do!
闭嘴，布赖恩特！
Shut up, Bryant!
Look at this.
斯特拉
Hey, Stella.
选一首慢歌吧
Make it a slow one.
Smile!
Alright, stand right here.
Alright. Stand real close!
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player